<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">

    <a name="origLanguage"></a>
    <h3>Original Language</h3>
    <p>
        Each <a href="StructureDefinition-ResearchStudy-IEHR.html">ResearchStudy-IEHR</a> MUST specify the original language of the content in the language attribute and the content of the attributes must be in this language.
    </p>

    <a name="translationRS"></a>
    <h3>Translation Instructions for the <a href="StructureDefinition-ResearchStudy-IEHR.html">ResearchStudy-IEHR</a></h3>
    <p>
        Only one RDD is published by the principal investigator and this RDD contains the content in all necessary languages.
    </p>

    <p>Translation of structured data</p>
    <ul>
        <li> Structured data is translated directly inside the attributes using the <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/R4/extension-translation.html">Translation Extension</a> </li>
        <li> For each attribute there should be one translation extension for each additional language</li>
    </ul>

    <p>Translation of <u>un</u>structured data</p>
    <ul>
        <li>Unstructured data is contained in a pdf and added in the ResearchStudy.relatedArtifact attribute</li>
        <li>Each pdf contain information in only one language and to translate the pdf a new file in the other language is created and added to the RDD</li>
    </ul>
    <p>As such the RDD references one pdf for each necessary language in the ResearchStudy.relatedArtifact</p>

    <a name="translationQuestionnaire"></a>
    <h3>Translation Instructions for the <a href="StructureDefinition-Questionnaire-IEHR.html">Questionnaire-IEHR</a></h3>
    <p>
        The questionnaire itself should only contain codes and no text.
        Thus, the questionnaire does not need to be translated, instead the translation is part of the CodeSystem referenced by the questionnaire.
    </p>
    <p>Handling of CodeSystems main attributes in a translation</p>
    <ul>
        <li>The original language of the system is described in the CodeSystems mandatory language attribute</li>
        <li>The representation of a code in the original language is specified in concept.display </li>
        <li>Translations are added as concept.designation attributes, with the concept.designation.value attribute containing the representation of the code in the language specified in the concept.designation.language attribute</li>
    </ul>

</div>
